<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
  <title>Library of Faculty of Education</title>
  <link>http://knihovna.pedf.cuni.cz</link>
  <description></description>
  <generator>Lettersmith</generator>
  <item>
    <title>Library Closed</title>
    <link>http://knihovna.pedf.cuni.cz</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;Our library had to be closed due to preventive measures following the
restrictions given by the Government of the Czech Republic until further
notice. We prolonged loans until November 18, 2020. All &lt;a href=&quot;catalogues.html&quot;&gt;e-resources&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; are
available 24 hours a day. Books can be returned in the Bibliobox next to the
reception desk. You can also mail them back to us. You can pay any &lt;a href=&quot;fees.html&quot;&gt;late fees by bank transfer&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feel free to use our online
advisory via FB
&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.facebook.com&#x2F;knihovnapedfpraha&quot;&gt;@knihovnapedfpraha&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;! We can help
you with access to a wide array
of electronic content, bibliographic references management, and lookup of literature.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
    <pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2020 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">&#x2F;2020-10-13-library_services_updates.md</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Art Exhibition Invitation - &quot;Transience&quot;</title>
    <link>http://knihovna.pedf.cuni.cz</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;How can a scientistic imaging method be artistically used? We are displaying
the art series of macrophotographs called Transience by professor Jan Valenta
from the Faculty of Mathematics and Physics. Come and take a look yourself!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
    <pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2020 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">&#x2F;2020-09-28-art_exhibition_invitation_-_transience.md</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Library temporarily closed</title>
    <link>http://knihovna.pedf.cuni.cz</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;We want to remain a safe place for everyone. Therefore, as a precaution, the
library will remain closed until the test results on COVID 19 are received. You
can still return books to the Bibliobox. We will inform you about the operation
in the following week on Monday, September 28, at the latest. Thank you for
your understanding.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
    <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2020 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">&#x2F;2020-09-23-library_temporarily_closed.md</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Share your experience with an open access</title>
    <link>http://knihovna.pedf.cuni.cz</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;What is important for you for the easiest publication of your open access articles? We will be glad if you complete this questionnaire.
We will analyze the current situation in the area of open acces in Charles University from your responses in the questionnaire.
You will find more detailed info on brand new &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;openscience.cuni.cz&#x2F;OSCI-1.html&quot;&gt;web for open science&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
    <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">&#x2F;2020-07-01-share_your_experience_with_an_open_access.md</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Use the opportunity to reserve a book in advance</title>
    <link>http://knihovna.pedf.cuni.cz</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;We recommend you to reserve a book in advance for avoding waiting in the queue.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How to order books:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Open CU Central Catalogue. Search the book and make a request for the
book situated in FEdu Magdalény Rettigové or FEdu Celetná.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Always return books to the library you borrowed them from. In
Magdalény Rettigové, you can return the books in the Bibliobox which
is situated next to the reception desk.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">&#x2F;2020-05-21-use_the_opportunity_to_reserve_a_book_in_advance.md</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Exhibition: Czech monuments from the 19th century</title>
    <link>http://knihovna.pedf.cuni.cz</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;Visit an exhibition in the Small Gallery next to the study room. You will see engraving of Czech monuments from
the 19th century and you can also win prices if you participate in our competition.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">&#x2F;2020-05-21-exhibition_czech_monuments_from_the_19th_century.md</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Book loans</title>
    <link>http://knihovna.pedf.cuni.cz</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;The loaning desk in the building in M. Rettigové street is open from Monday to Friday 9.OO-15.00. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Language Study Room Celetná is open every Wednesday from 9.00-14.30.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Books have to be
ordered in advance via the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;ckis.cuni.cz&#x2F;F&#x2F;8VS6TJL11VBAGNAQVX4EVGUR8M536Y2F2QIUSVSXT44JRI6X8H-35435?RN=563431407&amp;amp;pds_handle=GUEST&amp;amp;CON_LNG=ENG&quot;&gt;CU Central Catalogue&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.
When you find a book in the catalogue, make sure it is located in &lt;em&gt;FEdu M.
Rettigové&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;FEdu Celetná&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;. To make the request, choose the option &lt;a href=&quot;&#x2F;img&#x2F;library-request.png&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Request&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;  on
the left side&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; of the web page. The value in the &lt;em&gt;Due date&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; column has to be &lt;em&gt;On shelf&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;. When the
reservation is ready, we will send you a confirmation e-mail with further instructions.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Books borrowed in the M. D. Rettigové building can be returned only in the Bibliobox next to the reception desk.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
    <pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2020 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">&#x2F;2020-05-08-loans.md</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Use the opportunity to contact our online advisory centre</title>
    <link>http://knihovna.pedf.cuni.cz</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;If you are not sure where to find books in digital form and other
e-resources, use the opportunity to contact our online avisory centre.
We are here for you: &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;knihovna.pedf.cuni.cz&#x2F;JSMEONLINE&quot;&gt;knihovna.pedf.cuni.cz&#x2F;JSMEONLINE&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2020 11:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">&#x2F;2020-03-19-use_the_opportunity_to_contact_our_online_advisory_centre.md</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Library closed</title>
    <link>http://knihovna.pedf.cuni.cz</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;According to the quickly changing nature of the situation, the dean´s college
on March 10, 2020 decided: The PedF UK building will be accessible only to
teachers and staff with their Staff Card. Students are not allowed in the
building. All loans will be prolonged as necessary.
There is no need to return them in the original date. Please feel free to use
our e-resources for your studying: &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;ezdroje.cuni.cz&#x2F;index.php?lang=en&quot;&gt;ezdroje.cuni.cz&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.
For new information you can visit a web page &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;koronavirus.pedf.cuni.cz&quot;&gt;koronavirus.pedf.cuni.cz&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
    <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 11:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">&#x2F;2020-03-10-library_closed.md</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Exhibition Anticodes by Václav Havel</title>
    <link>http://knihovna.pedf.cuni.cz</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;Visit our new exhibition Anticodes &amp;ndash; visual poems by Václav Havel in the Small
Gallery next to the study room till the end of March. We appreciate the
cooperation with the Library of Václav Havel which has borrowed us the
Anticodes.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2020 11:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">&#x2F;2020-03-05-exhibition_anticodes_by_vaclav_havel.md</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Media database Anopress is now accessible from anywhere</title>
    <link>http://knihovna.pedf.cuni.cz</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;Media database Anopress contains full texts of peridodicals, radio
programmes and TV programmes from 1996 until today. It is now accessible
from anywhere for students and employees of Faculty of Education for
free!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2020 11:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">&#x2F;2020-02-06-media_database_anopress_is_now_accessible_from_anywhere.md</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Come to see the photo exhibition about Greenland</title>
    <link>http://knihovna.pedf.cuni.cz</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;Andrea Kalinová captured on her photos Arctic Circle Trail or 240 kilometers of
Greenland wilderness.
Come and enjoy the Nordic vibe in the Small Gallery next to the study room. The exhibition will last until
the end of the February.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2020 11:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">&#x2F;2020-02-06-come_to_see_the_photo_exhibition_about_greenland.md</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>New Language Study Room</title>
    <link>http://knihovna.pedf.cuni.cz</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;We are going to open a new Language Study Room in the Faculty building in Celetná street.
The opening will take place on 17th January 2020. Study room provides reference
literature, exercise books, monographies and specialised databases for
English, German and Russian language and literature Studies. More information
can be found &lt;a href=&quot;celetna-en.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
    <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2020 11:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">&#x2F;2020-01-17-new_language_study_room.md</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Limitation of Study room services </title>
    <link>http://knihovna.pedf.cuni.cz</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;On Tuesday, December 17, a Christmas meeting of faculty staff will take place
in the Study room. The Study room will be closed from 2pm to 5pm. We are sorry for
complications. You can then visit the reading room at regular times until Thursday December 19.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
    <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2019 11:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">&#x2F;2019-12-17-limitation_of_study_room_services_on_tuesday_december_17.md</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>New Library and Circulation Rules of CU</title>
    <link>http://knihovna.pedf.cuni.cz</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;Dear library user, we would like to inform you that the new Library and
Circulation Rules of CU become effective on the 1st of December 2019 (for
further information, please visit &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;cuni.cz&#x2F;UK-10054.html&quot;&gt;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;cuni.cz&#x2F;UK-10054.html&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;). New rules are
bringing innovation to library services. From the 1st of December 2019, you
won&amp;rsquo;t need a separate registration to each CU library, only one registration
for the use of CU libraries will be sufficient. Your current registration will
remain valid and will also be extended to every CU library. We believe that
this arrangement will facilitate access to literature and special collections
of CU libraries.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
    <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2019 11:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">&#x2F;2019-12-09-new_library_and_circulation_rules_of_cu.md</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>New reference desk</title>
    <link>http://knihovna.pedf.cuni.cz</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;We are happy to have a new furniture in our reference desk room. We planned it
in cooperation with our readers. Come to our library and enjoy!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">&#x2F;2019-09-12-new_reference_desk.md</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>A small change in the library services between 3rd and 6th September</title>
    <link>http://knihovna.pedf.cuni.cz</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;Because of a reconstruction of our Loan desk room between 3rd and 6th September
2019, we are ready to lend you books in the Study room during this time. It´s a
little bit challenge for us, but we look forward to seeing you, and to
newcomers in particular! We have automatically extended all borrowed books,
that should be returned at September 3th, 2019. A new due date for these books
is September 9th, 2019. Please feel free to use our big red box (Bibliobox)
next to the main entrance in the building, if you only want to return books and
you don´t need anything else in the library.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
    <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2019 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">&#x2F;2019-08-21-a_small_change_in_the_library_services_between_3rd_and_6th_september.md</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Opening hours in summer 2019</title>
    <link>http://knihovna.pedf.cuni.cz</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt; We are closed in July because of shelf checking. We are looking forward to see you each Tuesday in August, 9 a.m.-3 p.m. Please feel free to use our &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;ezdroje.cuni.cz&#x2F;index.php?lang=en&quot;&gt;e-resources&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
    <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">&#x2F;2019-07-01-opening_hours_in_summer_2019.md</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Study Room is open</title>
    <link>http://knihovna.pedf.cuni.cz</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;Good News!
Our Study Room was officially opened  after a long reconstruction.
It contains not only books, magazines and a quit place for study, but also computers with access to electronic journals, a printer or a scanner. Smaller team Study Room is available as well.
We look forward for your visit!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 11:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">&#x2F;2019-02-28-studyroom_is_open.md</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Temporary closing of the Library</title>
    <link>http://knihovna.pedf.cuni.cz</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;From Monday 4th to Thursday 7th February, the library will be closed due to the
moving of the circulation desk. The desk will be moved in front of the study room so you do
not have to go to two different places. The Bibliobox will work without
interruption. We look forward to seeing you in a brand new library!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
    <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 11:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">&#x2F;2019-01-29-temporary_closing_of_the_library.md</guid>
  </item>
</channel>
</rss>
